JOHN KEY

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

Phone: 931-703-8840

Email: jbkey2015@gmail.com

Personal Site: personal-bio-site-60fb3.firebaseapp.com

Github: https://github.com/jbkey2015 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jbkey/

ABOUT ME

I have been in retail for the past seven years. Working my way from a sales consultant to management. I enjoy working on a team to help push each other and be the best. I have always had a desire to be a web developer but wasn't sure where to begin. Then a friend of mine let me know about Nashville Software School. I began to do research and talked to some people who had been through boot camps and decided that this would be a good fit for me. It has definitely pushed me and there have been many tough times, but I enjoy the challenge and like that there is always something new to learn. I am eager to get into a career in this field and see where it takes me.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

JavaScript
React
CSS/SCSS
HTML
VS Code
Visual Studios
C#
ASP.net
Git and GitHub
Bootstrap

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Intensive, part-time, year-long software bootcamp covering the foundations and problem-solving skills related to Front and Back-End software development, catering to both individual and group work environments and experiences.

- Database/API utilizing Firebase, JSON, C#, SQL, promises, and axios calls
- Built single page applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, SCSS, and React
- Use wireframes, ERD's, and create tickets in planning
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Developed Console Applications using C#

PROJECTS

FRONT END CAPSTONE

Animal Rescue is an application to help animals get adopted. It allows people to view animals at different shelters and make donations to each individual animal. They can choose to donate towards adoption fees and even toys and supplies for the animals. This would make the upfront cost involved with getting a new pet a lot less and hopefully would make more people want to adopt.

https://animal-rescue-bc796.firebaseapp.com/https://github.com/jbkey2015/animal-rescue

WORK EXPERIENCE

ASSISTANT MANAGER-SIGNET JEWELERS 2013-2017, 2019-PRESENT

- Train and on-board new hires using company standards and training tools
- Lead sales floor when manager is traveling for business
- Ensure team knows what is needed to reach certain goals and provide constant mentorship
- If a team member is struggling help them create a plan to get them on track to where they need to be
- Individual game plans to enable staff to meet and/or exceed sales quotes

OFFICE MANAGER-GENESIS DIAMONDS 2017-2019

- Writing and processing orders for repairs and special orders
- Paying extra attention to detail while making quality checks on all repairs and special orders to ensure the pieces meet all the correct specifications
- Using Salesforce to gather client's information and keep track of what
 merchandise meets their satisfaction, as well as keeping track of all
 special dates and purchases to provide clients with new products and
 promotions later.
- Ensure team members are staying on track with meeting goals and provide solutions to help meet goals.
- Processing insurance paperwork on items purchased by client and providing clients with appraisals on merchandise purchased.
- Ensured all transactions match to payments received and take any deposits to the bank.